<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/changes/1.0.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/changes/1.0.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/changes-1.0.0.xsd">
  <body>

    <release version="2.00.00" date="2019-11-08" description="V2 of Sim0MQ with message classes and heartbeat">
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="update">
        Changed versions of djunits, djutils and dsol to the latest version to be compatible with Java 9+. 
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="add">
        Added separate classes for each message to make construction and information gathering more straightforward.
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="fix">
        Fixed numerous small errors in FederateServer and demo classes after tightening the checks. 
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="add">
        Added Heartbeat messages HB.1 (Heartbeat) and HB.2 (Alive). 
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="add">
        Added reference implementation for processing Heartbeat messages. In order to allow to send/receive heartbeat 
        messages between the other messages, the way that answers are received in the Java code had to be changed.
        The state machine of the different federates now has to allow for HB-messages to be sent and received
        between all other messages.    
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="add">
        Added reference implementation for the state machine of a Federation Manager.     
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="add">
        Added reference implementation for the state machine of a Model Controller.     
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="add">
        Changed the MM1FederationManager20 example in sim0mq-demo to work with an arbitrary folder that
        contains the model on the server where the FederateStarter is present.     
      </action>
    </release>
    
    <release version="1.01.01" date="2019-07-12" description="First version of FederateStarter unit test">
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="add">
        A first unit test for the reference implementation of the FederateStarter has been added. This test 
        communicates using port 5500 to the FederateStarter.
      </action>
    </release>
    
    <release version="1.01.00" date="2019-07-11" description="Complete messages; Unit tests">
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="update">
        For reproducibility: HashMap replaced by LinkedHashMap; HashSet replaced by LinkedHashSet.
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="add">
        Unit tests for FM, FS, MC messages implemented (and a number of errors resolved).
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="update">
        NumberDuration and NumberTime made more precise in terms of which object they represent.
      </action>
    </release>
    
    <release version="1.00.00" date="2019-07-04" description="Serializing / deserializing moved to djutils-serialization project">
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="update">
        Changes made to update deprecated methods in jeromq 0.5.1.
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="update">
        Since (de)serialization is more generic than just sim0mq, the classes to do (de)serialization have been moved to 
        a separate project called djutils-serialization. See https://djutils.org for more information.
      </action>
    </release>
    
    <release version="0.05.00" date="2018-08-11" description="Coding / decoding finished">
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="fix">
        Finalized coding / decoding for all types in the TypedMessage.
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="update">
        Update for DJUNITS version 3.00.07 to use instantiation helper classes.
      </action>
    </release>
    
    <release version="0.04.00" date="2018-08-09" description="Coding / decoding improved">
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="fix">
        Increased coding / decoding for more types in the TypedMessage.
      </action>
    </release>
    
    <release version="0.03.00" date="2018-08-07" description="Multithreading. New version of jeromq; ZContext instead of ZMQ.Context">
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="fix">
        Message loss in case of multi-threading repaired.
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="add">
        Several examples added in demo package to test multi-threading.
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="update">
        Used ZContext wrapper instead of ZMQ.Context.
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="fix">
        Included most types in the TypedMessage for coding and decoding.
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="add">
        Allowed for UTF8 or UTF16 encoding of messages.
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="update">
        Update for DJUNITS version 3.00.05.
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="update">
        Update for jeromq version 0.4.3.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.02.00" date="2017-05-01" description="DJUNITS and Money type updates">
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="update">
        Units and DisplayUnits adapted to the changes in DJUNITS version 3.00.01.
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="update">
        Two bytes used for the Money type as 255 is too low, and cannot store the
        standard currency id codes.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.01.00" date="2017-04-22" description="First version of the Sim0MQ Simulation Message Bus">
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="add">
        First version of type structure and message structure.
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="add">
        First version of the major messages of the Federation Manager, Federate
        Starter and Model.
      </action>
      <action dev="averbraeck" type="add">
        First version of the abstract versions of Federation Manager, as well as
        model implementations of the Federate Starter and Model.
      </action>
    </release>

  </body>
</document>